# Kumari Shivani

DATA ANALYST

## Contact

**Phone** 974 219 6301

E-mail

shivanikmri023@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivani-kumari-6a067a6

# **Skills**

Programming Language: R, Python, LINUX

Databases: MySQL

Statistics: Hypotheses Testing,
Bivariate and Multivariate
Analysis, Measure of
locations and spread

Supervised Machine
Learning: Regression,
Random Forest, Decision
Tree, Support Vector
Machine, XG-Boost,
Gradient Boosting, PCA
,Stochastic Models, ANN,
SIER, CNN, OpenCV, RNN,
Bayesian Models,
Forecasting,
TensorFlow/Keras, ETL,
Spyder plots, PDP plots,
Factor analysis, Word

Perceptive and logical data analyst with proven ability to communicate with both technical professionals and end users to identify and translate business requirements. Offering 4.2 years of experience driving data accuracy and integrity. Proven ability to build and lead teams of talented professionals to develop valuable process solutions to meet business objectives.

# **Work History**

2018-12 -Current

# **Data Analyst**

CERNER HEALTHCARE, BENGALURU, Karnataka

- Cataract Detector: Classification model build using OpenCV/CNN helped doctors with quicker classification and diagnosis.
- **Client Satisfaction:** Analysis of the data collected through the questionnaire to understand problem areas to improve client satisfaction.
- Robotic Process Automation: Process Automation of manual entry of medical bills to increase the turn around time for a claim.
- Document Classification/Similarity: Grouping similar documents that contain the failure status/area /reasons for easier resolutions and understanding reoccurring issues.
- Go-Live Delay Prediction: Studying the pattern during solution deployment to avoid go-live delays to reduce costs incurred.
- Call volume Forecasting and Staffing Model:
   Predicting the alarm inpour for each hour of operation and optimal staffing for efficient handling.
- File Recommendation: Prediction of similar files while files are changed to minimize the chances of a conflict.

2018-06 -2018-11

# **Data Analyst**

ALMUG TECHNOLOGIES, BENGALURU, Karnataka

- Loan Eligibility Prediction: Developed an analytical solution which underpins strategic loan grating after the state policy changed and the amount of data that could access had limitation's
- Loan Bucket Analysis: Analyzed the risk factor and

#### Embedding, Keras.

Unsupervised Machine Learning: K Means Clustering , Naive Bayes, Clustering, Recommendation System

Text Analytics: NLP,
Sentiment Analysis,
Text/Document similarity,
Word Embedding

Data Visualization: Power BI, DASH

- repaying capacity of an individual for loan amount granting.
- Debt Recovery: Worked with the Debt Buyer agency by helping them in debt buyout to minimizes the chances of defaulting and maximizing the return.
- Cluster Analysis: Pattern study of a defaulter to minimize risk. It helped the client to decide strategy, policies, and marketing.

### 2016-06 -2016-11

#### **ALVES TECHNOLOGIES**

PHP DEVELOPER, ZIRAKPUR, PUNJAB

- School Time: Website developed for multiple users based on the hierarchy of schools for better management.
- PM-Certy: Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.

#### 2015-02 -2016-02

# Software Developer

VIRTUOSO NETSOFT PVT. LTD., CHANDIGARH

- Ad Clicks: Model build to maximize ad clicks. Helped in deciding the time and pattern of ad posting. The strategy leads to an increase in revenue of 5%.
- · Market Analysis: Company's past performance in sales and marketing analyzed to restructure units to increase revenue and cut down operational costs.
- · IVRS SERVICES: Development and maintenance of IRVS.

# Education

2009-09 -

**B.TECH: CSE** 

2013-09

**BPUT - ODISHA** 

# **Certifications**

2017-10 IMARTICUS LEARNING - Data Science Pro Degree

2018-01 EDX.org - Analytics Edge